Marc Gaede Papers, 1910-1999.: Finding Aid C1436
Manuscripts Division
- Robert Sundance Working Files, 1910-1998; Sundance, Robert, 1927-1993; 21 boxes
  - Robert Sundance Personal and Family Materials, 1910-1998; 4 boxes
    Consists of personal and family papers of Robert Sundance collected by Marc Gaede, including drafts of short writings by Sundance (some of which contain revisions by Gaede), correspondence, documents, and photographs of Sundance throughout his life as well as of his family members.
    - Robert Sundance Writings, 1979-1982; 1 box
      - Robert Sundance, "Invidious System Rectified", 1980; 1 folder (Box B-000852, Folder 4)
      - Robert Sundance, "The Peyote Road Leads Home", 1979-1982; 1 folder (Box B-000852, Folder 5)
      - Robert Sundance, "Barbarous Practice of Los Angeles", 1979; 1 folder (Box B-000852, Folder 6)
      - Robert Sundance, "Not Guilty on Skid Row", undated; 1 folder (Box B-000852, Folder 7)
        Photocopy of published essay.
      - Robert Sundance, "A Novel", undated; 1 folder (Box B-000852, Folder 8)
        Consists of a single typed page.
    - Robert Sundance Correspondence, 1978-1993; 1 folder (Box B-000852, Folder 9)
    - Robert Sundance Documents, 1910-1998; 3 boxes
      - Robert Sundance Resumes, circa 1980s; 1 folder (Box B-000852, Folder 10)
      - Robert Sundance Family Financial, Medical, and Legal Documents, 1978-1998; 4 folders (Box B-000856, Folder 1-4)
        This material is closed until 2037.
      - Robert Sundance Wills, 1993 May 2-June 30; 1 folder (Box B-000853, Folder 1)
      - Robert Sundance Certification of Tribal Affiliation, 1979 November 14; 1 folder (Box B-000853, Folder 2)
        Photocopies.
      - Robert Sundance Funeral Programs, 1993 August; 1 folder (Box B-000853, Folder 3)
      - Robert Sundance Family Clippings, 1956-1991; 1 folder (Box B-000853, Folder 4)
      - Robert Sundance Copy of My Friend the Indian, 1910; 1 folder (Box B-000853, Folder 5)
        1st edition copy of the book by James McLaughlin, owned and inscribed by Robert Sundance on March 5th, 1977.
    - Robert Sundance Photographs, 1930-1993; 2 boxes
      - Robert Sundance Childhood Photographs, circa 1930s; 1 folder (Box B-000853, Folder 6)
      - Robert Sundance Youth and Military Service Photographs, circa 1943-1950; 3 folders (Box B-000853, Folder 7-9)
      - Robert Sundance Photographs, 1940s-1950s; 1 folder (Box B-000853, Folder 10)
        Includes photographs with family and friends, as well as landscapes.
      - Robert Sundance Photographs, 1970s; 1 folder (Box B-000853, Folder 11)
      - Robert Sundance Photographs, 1980s; 1 folder (Box B-000853, Folder 12)
      - Robert Sundance Photographs, circa 1990-1993; 1 folder (Box B-000853, Folder 13)
      - Robert Sundance and Marc Gaede Photographs, circa 1991-1993; 1 folder (Box B-000853, Folder 14)
        Includes some photographic negatives.
      - Robert Sundance "Cowboy Clothes and Haranguing the Masses" Photographs, circa 1970s-1992; 1 folder (Box B-000853, Folder 15)
      - Robert Sundance, Jack Pipe, Del Smith Photographs, circa 1970s-1985; 1 folder (Box B-000853, Folder 16)
      - "Smokey Riding High Branch on Glasseye" Photographs, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000853, Folder 17)
      - Pat McLaughlin Photographs, circa 1970s; 1 folder (Box B-000853, Folder 18)
        Pat McLaughlin was Robert Sundance's brother.
      - School Portraits of McLaughlin Family Children, 1970s; 1 folder (Box B-000854, Folder 1)
  - Administrative and Publishing Files, 1977-1995; 2 boxes
    Not arranged according to any arrangement scheme.
    Consists of correspondence, agreements, contracts, and notes by Gaede and Sundance pertaining to administrative and legal matters surrounding the publication of Sundance: The Robert Sundance Story by the Sundance/Gaede Collaborative, as well as to other projects involving the use of Sundance's life story. Agreements and contracts between Gaede and Sundance specify the conditions of their collaboration. Correspondence regards general publishing and editorial matters, as well as potential film deals and disputes over the depiction of aspects of Sundance's biography in nonfiction books by others, including Charles Bowden's Blood Orchid.
    - Sundance Book Publishing and Collaboration Agreements, 1991 August 12-1993 December 15; 1 folder (Box B-000854, Folder 2)
    - Sundance Book Publishing and Rights Correspondence and Agreements, 1991-1995; 3 folders (Box B-000854, Folder 3-5)
    - Marc Gaede Notes, 1991; 1 folder (Box B-000854, Folder 6)
    - Robert Sundance Notes and Contacts, undated; 1 folder (Box B-000854, Folder 7)
    - 20th Century Fox Film Deal Correspondence and Documents, 1980-1989; 2 folders (Box B-000854, Folder 8-9)
    - "Sundance Movie" Correspondence and Documents, 1977-1982; 1 folder (Box B-000855, Folder 1)
      Additional copies of correspondence and clippings regarding life rights Sundance organized into a binder.
- General Correspondence, 1976-1999; 2 boxes
  Arranged chronologically.
  Consists of general professional correspondence files spanning from the mid 1970s through the late 1990s. While these files are not comprehensive chronologically, they contain correspondence between Marc Gaede, and to a lesser extent, Marnie Gaede, with publishers, distributors, collaborators, colleagues, and activist organizations. Correspondents include Virginia Adams, David Lavender, Evan Connell, Clarke Abbey, and Robert Sundance, among many others. While original folder titles indicate that correspondence has to do with publishing, the actual contents of these files are somewhat broader. Materials relate to many of the book projects represented in Gaede's working files but also to teaching, conference travel, script analysis work for Disney, collaboration with the Sea Shepherd Conservation Society, and Chaco Press.
  - Publishing Correspondence, 1976-1978; 1 folder (Box B-000855, Folder 2)
  - Photography Correspondence, 1985-1986; 1 folder (Box B-000855, Folder 3)
  - Book Correspondence, 1989; 1 folder (Box B-000855, Folder 4)
  - Book Correspondence, 1990; 1 folder (Box B-000855, Folder 5)
  - Book Correspondence, 1994-1999; 1 folder (Box B-000855, Folder 6)
  - Restricted Correspondence, 1978-1994; 1 folder (Box B-000856, Folder 5)
    This material is closed until the death of Marc and Marnie Gaede due to the presence of personally identifiable information.